Binary search is searching algorithm for finding and elements position is sorted array.
And this approach, the element is always search in the middle of portion of an array, so binary search
can be implemented only on a sorted list of items.
If the elements are not sorted already, we need to sort them first.
Binary search algorithm can be implemented in two ways, which are discussed below and in the next videos.
We will see them in that in C and in Java, and we will get the examples about them.
So it would be an iterative method and in a recursive method.
So the recursive method follows that divide and divide and conquer approach that we have seen at in
the previous videos.
Don't worry, we will discuss everything in the next few years.
So the time complexities of the binary search in the best case, complexities of one finding the element
at the first root and the average case complexities o lug an average case complex is very important
because we have lugg and which is the tree, and it's the same as the worst case complexity, and we
have taken an example in that in the trees.
So binary search trees.
So if you need to go deeply inside the binary search trees and the binary search algorithm, please
go back to this to that tree section and search for minor surgery.
And let's find the example.
They're very good example about luck and how its calculation being calculated and how it's present.
Like Look and.
The space complexity is the space complexity of binary circuitry is of what it's very simple.
Now.
Let's move to implement the binary search tree or the bias or the binary search algorithm inside the
using the two ways that iteratively.